Have a blast.
Astro Boy is a animation, action, family film directed by David Bowers.
Set in the futuristic Metro City, Astro Boy (Atom) is a young robot with incredible
powers created by a brilliant scientist in the image of the son he had lost.
Unable to fulfill his creator's expectations, Astro embarks on a journey in search of acceptance, experiencing betrayal and a
netherworld of robot gladiators, before returning to save Metro City and reconcile with the father who rejected him.
Astro / Toby (voice), played by Freddie Highmore.
Cora (voice), played by Kristen Bell.
Hamegg (voice), played by Nathan Lane.
Orrin (voice), played by Eugene Levy.
Sparx (voice), played by Matt Lucas.
Dr. Elefun / Robotsky (voice), played by Bill Nighy.
Astro Boy is a 2009 animated superhero film loosely based on the manga series of
the same name by the Japanese writer and illustrator Osamu Tezuka.
Produced by the Hong Kong-based company Imagi Animation Studios, it was directed by
David Bowers, who co-wrote the screenplay with Timothy Hyde Harris.
The film stars Freddie Highmore, Kristen Bell, Nicolas Cage, Donald
Sutherland, Bill Nighy, Matt Lucas, Eugene Levy, Samuel L.
Jackson, Charlize Theron, and Nathan Lane.
In the film, Dr.
Tenma (Cage) creates Astro (Highmore), a teenage robot implanted with the
memories of his son after he is killed in an accident.
The pair face Stone (Sutherland), the president of Metro City who
is running for re-election, for their betrayal.
The film was first released in Hong Kong on October 8,
2009, and in the United States on October 23.
It received generally mixed reviews from film critics, but was a financial
failure, earning $42 million worldwide against its $65 million budget.
As a result of the film's bad performance, Imagi Animation Studios was shut down on
February 5, 2010; it became the last film produced by the studio.
The film explores themes of future, hero, superhero, based on manga, robot.
The tone is thought_provoking.